If we return to the Beta worldline...
If we undo that first D-Mail...
Being
Meltdown
You will die.
Even the billions of heartbeats in the world
suujuuoku mo no kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
are nothing to you but insignificant
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
Whether we’re trapped in the past or lamenting over the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
predetermination does not allow even the slightest mistake
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The infinite dreams and futures before us
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
are but vain privileges allowed to us
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finitude is what both clock hands show
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
toward a cruel destiny and choice
Hacking to the Gate
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
So now I cross worldlines every second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
because I want to protect that smile of yours
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no loop e to
And so, a time loop without sadness will once again
nomikomareteyuku kodoku no kansokusha
engulf me, the lone observer
So there you are.
If you keep lying there, you'll get heatstroke.
You sleep on the roof of the lab all the time anyway, don't you?
Besides, it's cloudy now.
Did you see Mayuri?
Hashida said he couldn't find her at ComiMa.
Yeah.
I met up with her after that.
I see.
Hey, Okabe.
What?
All right.
Hey.
It's raining.
What the fuck is this?!
Why didn't you warn me earlier?
I'm soaked down to my underwear.
I told you so.
It's your fault, Christina, for not listen—
Y-You pervert!
I wasn't exactly trying to look.
It's your fault for wearing such thin clothes.
I almost forgot you were such a pervert.
Who would want to see your featureless figure in the nude?
One more word, and I'll turn your neocortex into a flower pot!
What kind of threat is that?
Stay away from me!
What's that?
I got scratched somewhere while I was looking for you.
Klutz!
I'm what you'd call a "mad scientist."
Yeah, yeah.
You're so much trouble.
Hand that over.
I have a sewing kit on me.
I'll fix it up.
A sewing kit?
I consider myself more family oriented
than most people.
Take it off.
Just to be clear,
it's dark, so don't expect too much.
You can look forward to finding out what color thread I used after we leave.
Black, red, pink...
You have a 33% chance for each one.
I'll just pray it isn't pink.
Stay back.
Don't worry.
I'm not interested in that stick figure of yours.
I told you... A flower pot!
Geez...
Where could you have gone to rip your clothes like this?
Today,
I went to the lab,
to the laundromat,
and on a walk.
Then, I went to your hotel.
The hotel? You stopped by?
It's your fault.
You wouldn't answer my messages.
You weren't picking up your phone.
Were you worried about me?
As head of the lab, it's my job to keep track of my assistant.
Is it done yet?
Almost.
Here!
That's cold.
Hey!
Just put it on.
I'm not interested in the stick figure of a nude mad scientist.
It was probably around here, right?
The place I was stabbed...
How did you know?
The pain and despair were too real for a dream.
Kurisu,
you can't mean...
I have some hazy memories.
They're weak, almost nonexistent memories,
and not just of being stabbed.
I also remember you a little bit.
How desperate you were to save Mayuri.
How you kept pressing forward,
in pain and all alone.
You haven't made it back to your original world,
yet you kept going,
kept calling her name,
kept crying...
and kept trying to save her.
Every time I see that face,
I think about how important she is to you...
and whether it's possible for someone
to truly care for another person that much.
That's why I wanted to work with you.
That's why I wanted to help you.
Okabe,
save Mayuri.
You must save her.
If we go to the Beta worldline,
you'll die!
But it's the only way.
You know that better than anyone, right?
There's only one option.
Stop!
You're telling me to abandon you?
Is there any other way?
I've been thinking about it since yesterday.
"Isn't there some other way?"
"Isn't there something else we can do?"
But this time, I can't come up with anything...
except going to the Beta worldline.
Okabe!
I refuse to accept this.
I won't give up!
I can't...
I can't abandon Kurisu.
I can't let her die while I keep on living.
What would be the point?
I...
You can run away.
You can run away,
but that'll just make it worse!
Shut up!
No matter how many times you time leap,
you can't get past the 1% barrier!
We won't know until we try!
You'll just see Mayuri die...
again.
It'll destroy you.
It won't.
How many times do you think I've watched her die?
I've seen it over...
and over and over and over
and over and over.
It won't destroy me.
It doesn't matter how many times I see it!
Do you hear what you're saying?
Mayuri's going to suffer and die.
How can you say it doesn't matter?
If that doesn't affect you,
then your heart's already broken.
Just stop...
or you'll really break.
I know.
I noticed it long ago.
No matter how many times Mayuri died, I stopped being surprised.
I became desensitized without even knowing it.
Sometimes, I even waited before time leaping, just to see when she'd die.
At some point,
it just stopped affecting me.
Somewhere inside, I was calmly telling myself that I could do it over.
Save Mayuri.
If you don't,
it'll truly destroy you.
If you let her die,
you'll regret it for sure!
You and I have come this far with our only wish being to save her!
If we stop, we'll only regret it.
But if we save her,
you'll—
I'll just go back
to the first worldline, before the D-Mail was sent!
That's what's best for me,
and it's what's best for you too!
How many times have we fought over these past 20 days?
We made fun of each other.
We talked about our problems.
When my back was against the wall,
I turned to Kurisu.
Kurisu was the one who listened to me,
who believed in me.
At 18, she was already a genius with a published academic paper.
Always calm, always strong-willed,
always so proud and nosy,
but also always so kind and honest.
Her theories continually amazed me,
and I remembered everything she said
and watched everything she did.
She wasn't just another lab mem.
To me, Makise Kurisu was...
I can't save you.
I'm sorry.
Thank you
for going through so much for me.
Why was it you?
Why you?!
Hey,
what does it mean to change worldlines?
Maybe the second you go to the Beta worldline,
you'll just disappear from this world.
Or maybe you trade places with another Okabe.
That doesn't matter.
That's not true.
I'm not dead.
Even if I'm dead in the Beta worldline,
there's no guarantee that I'm going to die here!
There could be another me
amidst all the other infinite worldlines,
and our minds are connected and comprise "me."
Don't you think that'd be wonderful?
You'd be everywhere in every timeline, all at once.
A great love for someone,
a great belief in something,
a great desire to pass on something...
If all those things surpass time itself and create "you,"
wouldn't that be wonderful?
So don't think of it as abandoning me.
Even if the worldline changes,
as long as you don't forget me, I'll be there.
So...
I'll never forget you.
I won't forget the person I care for most.
Does that mean...
It's the truth.
H-How?
This is so sudden.
I'm in love with you.
What about you?
What do you mean?
I want to hear your response.
How do you feel about me?
You want to know?
Yeah.
Your face.
Close your eyes.
Why?
Just do it!
I-I didn't want to do that, okay?
But experiences such as your first kiss
are stored in the hippocampus with your strong memories,
which are harder to forget.
Thus—
Sorry.
That wasn't my first kiss.
You insolent virgin!
Silence, little girl.
My first kiss wasn't at all romantic.
Anyway...
that last one only left a weak impression.
How about one more?
I don't want to forget, not ever,
so I'll take extra care.
Well, I guess that's okay.
Just a kiss, right?
Time is passing so quickly.
Right now,
I feel like complaining to Einstein.
You know, Okabe,
whether time passes slowly or quickly
depends on your perception.
The theory of relativity is so romantic...
and so sad.
Goodbye then.
Are you sure about not saying it to Mayuri and Daru?
Everyone seeing me off would just make it worse.
If it's only you,
I can leave Japan without any hesitation.
That was a joke.
Here's a present.
Take it.
I don't want this.
I upgraded it to version 2.67.
What a pain.
But I'll take it anyway.
Bye.
Kurisu!
Right...
This is for you!
Where were you aiming?
Go get it.
Geez...
Okabe...
I'm sure that whatever happens, you're going to suffer.
Only you will remember me
in a world where no one else does.
More than anyone else, you care for your friends,
so it'll be painful for you.
I'm sorry.
But somehow, I'm glad you'll carry that pain.
For those times when you're sitting around the lab...
When you drink a can of juice...
When you walk around town...
And someday, when you kiss someone...
It doesn't have to be every time.
It can be one time out of a hundred,
but I'd like you to remember me
because I'll be there.
I'll be there,
beyond the 1% barrier!
Okabe...
Okabe.
Okabe!
Oh, shit!
Okarin, I found it.
This is it.
This is totally it!
If we delete this...
Mission complete.
Okarin,
are you okay?
I'm fine...
We now begin the final phase of Operation Verthandi!
Our victory is nigh!
We've overcome all conspiracies,
upholding our ideals to the very end.
And finally,
we've fought through the battle of Ragnarok!
I thank those who've worked so hard for me
to ensure this victory!
I am grateful to all those I've had to sacrifice.
What comes now is the world I wished for!
This is all the choice of Steins Gate!
This world...
will be rewritten!
Kurisu...
Forgive me.
Okabe!
Okabe...
I'm also...
Kurisu!
I also love...
Mayuri,
who is Lab Mem 004?
004?
There isn't a 004.
Now!
The battle of Ragnarok is undone!
I, the mad scientist, Hououin Kyouma, have conquered time itself,
foiling the Organization and SERN's schemes,
and brought about complete victory!
The world's power structure has been reset,
and a future of chaos awaits!
This is the choice of Steins Gate!
Okarin,
it's okay.
What are you saying?
I just issued a declaration of victory.
You don't have to talk like that anymore.
Mayushii is okay,
so you can cry for yourself, Okarin.
We no longer need the PhoneWave.
I met Kurisu because of it,
but,
it also hurt so many others.
Just as Hououin Kyouma has died,
the PhoneWave should die as well.
Living should mean no do-overs.
This is for the best.
Right, Kurisu?
Hello?
Huh?
Wh-Who's this?
"Dad"?
What?
Okarin?
Okarin, there's a strange girl who wants to talk to you!
Who's this?
Please come to the roof of Radio Kaikan immediately!
Who are you?
I've come from the year 2036.
I'm Hashida Itaru's daughter,
Amane Suzuha!
Suzuha?
Wait!
What are you doing here?
Please believe what I'm about to tell you.
You must stop World War III.